LIU-DI LU

7-9 Rue du Conseil-Général, 75005, Genève, Suisse

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My Ph.D research is principally devoted to modeling, control and optimisation of the industrial algal raceway ponds. Meanwhile, I also work on Model Order Reduction applied on PDE problems. Recently, I start to work on Domain Decomposition problem and Parallel space time methods.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Post-doc contract

October 2021 - present

University of Geneva, Geneva

Monitor contract

October 2018 - September 2021

Sorbonne University, Paris

192h teaching duty

Doctoral contract

October 2018 - September 2021

Sorbonne University, Paris

Modelization and Optimisation for coupling hydrodynamics-photosynthesis systems

 ${\bf Research\ Internship}$

March 2018 - September 2018

Inria Paris team ANGE

Model Reduction for Burgers' equation

EDUCATION

Laboratory Jacques-Louis Lions, Sorbonne University, Paris, France

2018 - 2021

Ph.D thesis under the supervision of Julien Salomon, Jacques Sainte-Marie (INRIA Paris team ANGE) and Olivier Bernard (INRIA Sophia Antipolis team BIOCORE)

Sorbonne University, Paris, France

2016 - 2018

Master degree in Mathematics and Applications

University Claude Bernard Lyon 1, Lyon, France

2015 - 2016

Bachelor degree in Mathematics

University Savoie Mont Blanc, Chambery, France

2013 - 2015

First and second year of Bachelor in Mathematics

PREPRINTS

Shape optimization of a microalgal raceway to enhance productivity, with Olivier Bernard, Jacques Sainte-Marie and Julien Salomon, submitted, 2020

Optimization of mixing strategy in microalgal raceway ponds, with Olivier Bernard and Julien Salomon, submitted, 2021

Optimal optical conditions for Microalgal production in photobioreactors, with Olivier Bernard, submitted, 2021

Theoretical growth rate of microalgae under high/low-flashing light, with Olivier Bernard and J. Ignacio Fierro U., submitted, 2021

PROCEEDINGS

Mixing Strategies Combined with Shape Design to Enhance Productivity of a Raceway Pond, with Olivier Bernard and Julien Salomon, published in 11th IFAC SYMPOSIUM on Advanced Control of Chemical Processes, 2021

Optimizing microalgal productivity in raceway ponds through a controlled mixing device, with Olivier Bernard and Julien Salomon, published in 2021 American Control Conference, 2021

Controlling the bottom topography of a microalgal pond to optimize productivity, with Olivier Bernard and Julien Salomon, published in 2021 American Control Conference, 2021

TALKS

| Geneva, November 2, 2021 | Microalgal raceway ponds modelling and optimization problems University of Geneva, Mathematics Section, Numerical Analysis Sem- |
|--------------------------------|---|
| Venice, June 13, 2021 | inar Mixing Strategies Combined with Shape Design to Enhance Productivity of a Raceway Pond 11th IFAC SYMPOSIUM on Advanced Control of Chemical Processes |
| Sophia Antipolis, June 3, 2021 | 2021 Some optimization problems in an algal raceway pond |
| • , , , | Inria Sophia Antipolis, Seminar of team BIOCORE |
| Online, May 28, 2021 | Shape design combining with a mixing device in an algal raceway pond 8th EGRIN school |
| New Orleans, May 25, 2021 | Optimizing microalgal productivity in raceway ponds through a controlled mixing device |
| | 2021 American Control Conference |
| New Orleans, May 25, 2021 | Controlling the bottom topography of a microalgal pond to optimize productivity |
| | 2021 American Control Conference |
| Toulouse, May 18, 2021 | Some optimization problems in an algal raceway pond |
| | Institut de Mathématiques de Toulouse, Seminar Modelisation, Analysis and Calcul |
| Online, December 3, 2020 | Optimization problem for a microalgal raceway pond to enhance productivity |
| | CAN-J 2020 (seminar of numerical analysis organized by SMAI) |
| Paris, November 4, 2020 | $Optimization\ problems\ of\ a\ microalgal\ raceway\ to\ enhance\ productivity$ |
| D 4 35 00 0040 | Inria Paris, Seminar of team ANGE |
| Paris, May 28, 2019 | Réduction de modèle pour l'équation de Burgers |
| Davis Daramban 12, 2019 | Ph.D seminar of Laboratory Jacques-Louis Lions |
| Paris, December 12, 2018 | Model Reduction for hyperbolic Equations Inria Paris, Seminar of team ANGE |
| | mna rans, semmar or team ANGE |

TEACHING

University of Geneva

2021-2022 Analyse II - Analyse Réelle

Sorbonne University

2019-2020 1MA001 Mathématiques pour les Sciences 1

DU Retour aux Etudes Supérieures pour les Personnes Exilées

2018-2019 1M001 Analyse et algèbre pour les sciences

3M236 Méthodes numériques pour les équations différentielles DU Retour aux Etudes Supérieures pour les Personnes Exilées

SKILLS

Computer Skills MATLAB, Python, Git, HTML, CSS

Languages Chinese, French, English